hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and I help coaches
authors speakers course creators and
mentors get more clients and make more
money than they ever imagined was
possible by using online marketing
direct sales
webinars Facebook ads and our techniques
to increase their business overall okay
so today I want to talk about why less
is more why simple ugly landing pages
work way better than complex ones this
is a big common misconception when I
work with a lot of people is that they
believe that the more complex the
landing page is the better the more
features uh the better graphics the more
prettier it is I'll tell you that you
know again I'm I love design I love
things looking great but honestly a
simple page works much better most of
the time the problem is is that a lot of
that prettiness actually becomes a
distraction and keeps people from
engaging with you it becomes
psychologically even overwhelming to
people so this is why Simplicity often
converts which is the craziest part
about it because most people that I meet
think that the more time they spend on
making it look more perfect the more
sales they're going to get when the
truth is most of the time that is not
even the case in fact it can hurt them
in fact it can cause more problems than
good one of the biggest issues that
coaches and mentors exper they're trying
to look like they got it all figured out
and they got it all together to people
you don't need that even if your
Marketplace expects it even if you might
have colleagues that are going to Raz
you or make you think that oh that
doesn't look good enough to put out
there publicly I want to see you make
money and what that means is that means
you going against the grain and against
the flow what everybody else is telling
you is the right way to do things if it
was the right way more people would be
successful with it problem is people
spend and invest a lot of time into
making their landing page super fancy a
lot of complexity adding a lot of
different things like that and it just
doesn't help it doesn't improve the
results it doesn't make things come
together better so what you want to do
is you want to instead of focusing in on
the landing page looking super
professional this is something I hear
from a lot of people I got to make my
stuff look professional enough so that
my reputation is maintained so that
people think good things about me and
they think that I'm a pro and then they
want to trust working with
me and the F and that's the furthest
thing from the truth that's the furthest
thing from what
actually produces
results your sales copy the words that
are on the page are more
important the actual words that you use
to connect with people the actual words
that speak to the emotional aspects of
the client and we need to speak from a
fourth grade to a seventh grade reading
level that's like speaking to an an
8-year-old to a 13-year-old that level
why is that because that's where a lot
of people's personality is formed and
you got to use the
words that the emotional side of their
brain comes from the unconscious mind
and that's what you need to speak to and
so what often happens is you end up
tapping into the logical and the
consciousness mind and they end up
talking themselves out of working with
you because everything looks
professional instead when you keep it
simple there's not as many distractions
and you're able to go deep into the core
of what actually triggers the buying
action from you and that's what your
goal is you want to positively trigger
people to take action when they visit
your landing page when they visit your
offer you know I've been teaching this
for a while and yet I constantly find
coaches and mentors who don't do it they
think oh they know better oh or I hear
this objection oh my Niche is different
Jeremiah it's not that is your belief
that is tied to a lack of experience
based on you comparing yourself to other
people that you see as successful one of
the biggest mistakes that you can make
is looking at a more successful person
and thinking that you need to just look
like them in your business they didn't
get there because they look that way
they generally present themselves in
that way once they arrived at that level
and that's the big fallacy that a lot of
people have about making things look
beautiful you want to make them be
minimal okay you want to clearly Express
things and this is about using
Neuroscience to be able to tap into the
psychological triggers that get people
to take action instead of creating
barriers and complexity and causing
people to second guess if they want to
engage with you because of all the fancy
dooh hickies bells and whistles that
you're doing that are on there okay so
understand if you want to produce better
results more sales increase the level of
trust that you have with people and
actually show up as an authority in your
Niche then you need to do the very thing
that goes against what seems like the
best way to do it which is to spend so
much energy making things all complex
making them very detailed very beautiful
them all look perfectly that's what your
brain is going to try to convince you is
the best way to do things and yet it is
the most
wrong the best way simple we have a
formula that we teach people where you
use Simple Graphics from canva and some
stock photos and the rest of the page
uses either headline text which is just
a little bit larger and those headlines
Express what the result the dream that
people are going to get is and then from
there
everything else is just simple black and
white
text going beyond that level of quote
unquote quality and
professionalism is a recipe for failure
and
disaster don't do
it if I could reach through the computer
and tell you this and get you to
understand what I know you would be more
successful and you would not be doing
that you would not be spending so much
energy perfecting the sales page
perfecting the way that it looks
perfecting perfecting how you present
yourself to people and the big mistake
is that people are trying to set a good
first impression by making things look
professional you want to repel the
people that are not a good fit and
attract the right ones and again I don't
care what your Niche is when it comes to
this industry coaching mentoring
training creating online
courses
complex is the enemy of
success
Simplicity simple enough that it does
not take a lot of thinking for the
person to register with
you one of the biggest problems that
happens is we get people tapping into
their thinking mind and out of their
emotional feeling brain and now they
second guess us and that hurts your
business okay so keep things simple
another benefit to this is it's not
going to take you as long putting offers
together is not going to take you as
much effort it's not going to take you
as many hours and that's the funny thing
about it is a lot of people like I don't
know all the technical side to do things
you don't have to know it because half
the time 90% of the quote unquote super
technical stuff that people think that
they need to do is a waste of time it's
worthless it's useless it's a waste of
resources and so keeping it simple is
going to produce the best result overall
people are even moving away from the
traditional landing page we're noticing
more and more people are going to link
trees and then they're going to even
being sold on a Google doc they're being
sold in the direct messages and the
sales copy is moving from even being
written to to being spoken like video
sales letters and vsls and this trend
has been happening for a while but it's
more it's accelerating and becoming more
and more that way because people are
impatient simple sells complex
fails and super pretty polished making
you quote unquote look Pro is way too
complex for your goals you want to find
the people that you can imp
impact build trust with them and by the
way complex is not the way to build
trust the trust is not built by your
page looking you presenting yourself as
a pro it's about the words that come out
of your mouth and your ability to tap
into those emotional triggers to get
people to take
action focusing that energy on the sales
copy and then dialing that in learning
to become really proficient with using
chat GPT and artificial intelligence
tools to be able to do that is where you
should be putting your energy not on
perfecting the profession ISM of your
landing page
okay and so if you can start doing this
you can be more successful I don't want
to see you fail and I don't want to see
you struggle yeah this is an area that I
see so many people struggling with
needlessly because they think that they
I've even heard it people think that
they know better than what I'm talking
about because quote unquote they saw
somebody else doing something
differently and that's one of I don't
mean this sound
arrogantly but that's one of the
stupidest things I've seen people do and
they do it a lot they do it
often I want to see you make a ton of
money and not spend a bunch of hours
doing it not spend a bunch of time not
delay not procrastinate and yet this is
one of those areas that literally is
fuel for
procrastination it's
disappointment
instead of keeping it
simple reaching people getting them on
your email list and then selling to them
and not worrying how do I look to
others not worrying if people quote
unquote reject you because you don't
quotee unquote look like somebody they
should
trust you got to get rid of that
thinking out of your brain that that
matters it doesn't not in this business
it might in other Industries not in this
industry and if you want to be
successful financially you'll do this if
you don't you can keep doing it the
other way that is a big fat waste of
time and energy that is actually going
to harm your results that is actually
going to hurt the overall efforts of
everything on so many dimensions and
levels or you can
choose to follow a path that's proven
that gets results and that's what I'm
talking about here today
simple is the
path simple is the
way and that's what I Mentor my clients
on and that's what I'd love to help you
with as well make sure to join us in one
of our live events that we're hosting
any of the upcoming events that we're
doing such as on Facebook ads starting
your business how to start and grow
things how to create your offers how to
create incredible landing pages that get
results and I can't wait to see you
become successful as a coach trainer and
Mentor be sure to share this episode
with somebody maybe somebody who's
spending a bunch of wasted time on
creating The Perfect Landing Page in the
perfect offer and I will see
you on the other side when you're making
way more money than you ever imagined
we'll talk
[Music]
[Applause]
soon